Alexander Hamilton
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Legal File, 1708-1804, n.d. (Box 26-35, Reel 22-29)
  Agreements, affidavits, briefs, client financial papers, contracts, memoranda, and notes.
  Arranged in two parts. The first grouping is organized alphabetically by name of case or client. The second part is arranged by type of material and chronologically within.
  - Alexander v. Byron (Box 26, Reel 22-23)
  - Anderson v. Thompson
  - Apthorp, Ward
  - Arden v. Johnson
  - Armstrong v. Destourelles
  - Armstrong v. Domerque
  - Arnold v. Pearsall
  - Arnoldie v. Price and Haywood
  - Ashfield, Richard, estate of
  - Aspinwall, John, estate of
  - Atwood v. Metcalf
  - Audibert v. Pillett
  - Ayscough, Richard, estate of
  - Bache v. Livingston
  - Bacon v. Morris and Wadsworth
  - Bacon and Stroud v. Tinker
  - Bank of New York v. Eden
  - Bank of the United States v. McGregor
  - Barcklay v. Wickham
  - Barnwell v. Church
  - Bartholomew v. Causaban
  - Baxter and Hunt v. Palmer
  - Bayard v. Cruger
  - Bayley v. Bazing
  - Bedient v. Church
  - Beebee and Barlow v. Bank of New York
  - Beeker v. Eden
  - Beekman v. Hunt
  - Beekman v. Low
  - Beekman v. Stuyvesant and Billings
  - Beekman, Beekman, and Gould v. Paulding
  - Beekman, Henry and Gertrude, estate of (Box 27, Reel 23-24)
  - Belknap v. Van Cortlandt
  - Benson v. Robinson
  - Bibbey v. Bayard
  - Bibbey v. Lawrence
  - Bibbey v. Wickham
  - Birdsall v. Hewlett
  - Birdsall v. Valentine
  - Blagge v. New York Insurance Co.
  - Blair v. Guion
  - Blair v. Vanderlocht
  - Bleecker and March v. Jay and Rivington
  - Bloodgood v. Launey
  - Bloodgood v. Sing
  - Bogart v. Livingston
  - Bogert v. Kingsley
  - Boyd v. Riley and Wetmore
  - Brantingham v. Inman and Grimm
  - Brasher (or Brazier) v. Knox
  - Brasher v. Kortright
  - Brooks v. Geary
  - Brott v. Gracie For additional material see Container 29, Graham v. Low
  - Brown v. Cummings
  - Brown v. Thomas
  - Brown v. Brown
  - Brush v. New York
  - Brush v. Stratton
  - Bryson v. Duryee
  - Bryson v. Goodrich
  - Bryson v. McGechran
  - Bryson v. New York Life Insurance Co.
  - Buchey v. Magnac and Magnac
  - Buisson v. United States
  - Burnet v. Van Horne
  - Byvanck v. Chadwell
  - Campbell v. Binden
  - Campbell v. Mordecai
  - Carpenter v. Mott and Mott and Carpenter v. Quimby
  - Casenave v. Stoughton
  - Cazeau v. Price and Haywood
  - Cheesemen v. Laurence
  - Cherry v. Byrne
  - Cherry v. Gouverneur
  - Childs v. Sands
  - Church v. Minturn and Champlin
  - Church v. Penfield and Van Rensselaer
  - Church v. United Insurance Co.
  - Clason v. Blair
  - Clifton Park
  - Cochran v. Beverly Robinson estate
  - Cochran v. Heard
  - Codwise v. Leary
  - Coit v. Morse and Coit v. Bull
  - Columbia College, New York, N.Y., Frederick Rhinelander's lease of college lots
  - Cooper v. Inman
  - Cork, William
  - Cornwell (or Cornell) v. Hendricksen
  - Cornwell (or Cornell) v. Shaw
  - Cowper v. Livingston
  - Craigie v. Bronson, Pomeroy, and Fowler
  - Creson v. Causaban
  - Crevecoeur v. Steuben (Box 28, Reel 24)
  - Cruger v. Low
  - Cruger v. Ward, Ward, and Ward
  - Cruger v. Low
  - Cruger v. Kortright
  - Currie v. Brown
  - Danneman v. Wetmore
  - Deane v. Nicoll
  - DeCastra v. Causaban
  - Dennis v. Prentice
  - Derue [?] v. Van Cortlandt and Bayard
  - Deschant v. LeBruen
  - Devoue v. Hunt
  - Dewindt v. Vanderlocht
  - Dickinson, Beletie
  - Dickinson v. Luddington and Wilcocks
  - Dod v. Bell
  - Doe v. Roe
  - Doughty, Isaac, estate of
  - Drake v. Quimby
  - Duboys v. Debrosses
  - DuCalvet v. Price and Haywood
  - Duer v. McCrea
  - Duff v. Laurance and Van Zandt
  - Dunlap and Van Nostrant v. Anderson
  - Durie v. Stuyvesant and Billings
  - Duryee v. Pemart
  - Episcopal Church v. [?]
  - Fairchild v. Shivers and Rhodericks and Robinson v. Shivers and Rhodericks
  - Fardon v. Holst
  - Field v. Beamun
  - Finlay and Gregory v. Price and Haywood
  - Flagg v. Thompson, Thompson, and Cruger
  - Foltz and Lorenzo v. Banks
  - Fonda v. Jenkins
  - Forrester v. Quackenboss
  - Fottrell v. Sutton
  - Franklin v. Weir
  - Franklin v. Slingerlandt
  - Franks v. Mercer and Mercer
  - Fraunces v. Gifford
  - Fretwell, Peter
  - Frisbie v. Crane
  - Gansevoort v. Boon
  - Gardiner v. Grenell
  - Gardiner and Wilson v. Hart and McDonald
  - Gardiner v. Sebor
  - Garrick and Westphal v. Elting
  - Garrick and Westphal v. Lindley
  - Garrineau v. Oakley
  - Gelston, Hurlbut, and Caulkins v. Parsons
  - Genter, John and Elizabeth, estates of
  - Georgia lands
  - Gerhart v. Apple
  - Gernon v. Church
  - Gilbert and Farquharson v. Hallett
  - Gilchrist v. Skinner
  - Girard v. Armstrong and Barnwall
  - Goadsby and Co. v. Brebner and Brown
  - Goadsby and Co. v. Moses and Co.
  - Goix v. United Insurance Co.
  - Goldthwaite v. Payne
  - Gomez v. Bowne and Rickman (Box 29, Reel 24-25)
  - Gomez v. Lopez
  - Gomez v. Maule
  - Gomez and Rivera v. Gouverneur
  - Goold and Goold v. Scott
  - Gouverneur v. LeGuen
  - Gouverneur v. Cooper
  - Graham v. Low and Brott v. Gracie
  - Graham v. Merritt and Merritt
  - Grant v. Bissett
  - Grozart v. Service and Service
  - Hagaman v. Young
  - Hallett v. Houston and Skidmore
  - Hallett and Bowne v. Jenks
  - Hamilton v. Duryee
  - Hardy v. Seton
  - Hargrave v. Cochran
  - Harris, George
  - Harris, Richard, estate of
  - Hart v. L'Epine
  - Hart v. Rogers
  - Hart and McDonald v. Gardner and Wilson
  - Hartt v. Wickes
  - Hatfield v. Van Cortlandt
  - Hawkins v. Brenan
  - Hawkins v. Smith
  - Hayton v. Allen
  - Hazard v. Van Cortlandt
  - Heath v. Ludlow
  - Henderson v. Butler
  - Henderson, Morton, and Pollock v. Brown
  - Hendricksen v. Cornwell
  - Heydecker v. Gilbert, Johnson, and King
  - Hickman v. Moses and Co. (Box 30, Reel 25-26)
  - Hodgson v. Bakewell
  - Hogg, Gilbert, estate of
  - Homan v. Carter
  - Hopkins v. Kemble
  - Hopkins v. Valentine and Coles
  - Howard v. Deane
  - Howell v. Desbrosses
  - Hurst v. DePeyster
  - Hylton, Daniel L.
  - Ingraham, Nathaniel G.
  - Ivers v. Stanton
  - Jackson v. Jackson
  - Jackson v. Van Rensselaer and Cully
  - Jackson ex dem. Burns v. Stiles and Ten Eyck
  - Jackson ex dem. Carpenter v. Moott (or Moot)
  - Jackson ex dem. Delaney v. Stiles and Delavan
  - Jackson ex dem. Ditman v. Stiles and Hotland
  - Jackson ex dem. Hargrave v. Cockran
  - Jackson ex dem. Haviland v. Haviland
  - Jackson ex dem. Hoghland v. Stiles and Hamilton
  - Jackson ex dem. Jay and Van Cortlandt v. Stiles and Rhinlander
  - Jackson ex dem. Leonard v. Post
  - Jackson ex dem. Livingston v. Hoffman
  - Jackson ex dem. Livingston v. Moore
  - Jackson ex dem. Ludlow v. Guernsey and Jones
  - Jackson ex dem. Lydig v. Turmont and tenant
  - Jackson ex dem. Mersereau v. Cornwall
  - Jackson ex dem. Mersereau v. Stiles and Cornwall
  - Jackson ex dem. Penfield and Van Rensselaer v. Fonda
  - Jackson ex dem. Prior and Knapp v. Voorhees and Brown
  - Jackson ex dem. Servis v. Stiles and Boon
  - Jackson ex dem. Trustees of Kingston v. Trumbous [?]
  - Jackson ex dem. Van den Bergh v. Breese
  - Jackson ex dem. Voght v. Ruffe
  - Jackson ex dem. Woodhull v. Rumsey
  - Jacobs and Jacobs v. Dunkley
  - Jay v. Barclay
  - Jay v. Rivington and Rivington
  - Jewell v. Stockholm
  - Jones v. Murray
  - Jordan v. Price and Haywood
  - Jordo v. Causaban
  - Kane v. Bank of New York
  - Kendrick v. Delafield
  - Keteltas v. Van Horne
  - Ketland v. Backhouse
  - Kiesselbach v. Falkenham and Wilmerding
  - King and King v. Thomas
  - King v. Cuyler
  - Kingston v. Wynkoop
  - Knox v. Moore and Moore
  - Koch v. Guion, Guion, and Carthy
  - Lansing v. Cortelyou (Box 31, Reel 26)
  - Laport v. Henry
  - Latham, James
  - Latting, Hain, and Birdsall v. Guest
  - Lawler v. Keaquick
  - Lawrence v. Cannon
  - Lawrence v. Palmer
  - Lawrence and Whitney v. Van Horne and Clarkson
  - Leavenworth v. Bowne
  - Leavenworth v. Dale
  - Leavenworth v. Delafield
  - LeConte v. LeConte
  - Lee and Lee v. Hart
  - Lefferts and Suydam v. Hammond
  - LeGuen, Louis
  - LeGuen v. Gouverneur
  - L'Hommedieu v. Hewlett
  - Lemoyne v. Price and Haywood
  - Lenox v. Juhel and Delonquemare
  - Leonard, Catharine
  - LeRoy and Bayard v. Shaw
  - LeRoy, Bayard, and Boon v. Servis
  - Lewis v. Burr
  - Lewis v. Cotton
  - Livingston v. Cooper
  - Livingston v. Godfrey
  - Livingston v. Hicks
  - Livingston v. Jamieson
  - Livingston v. Luddington
  - Livingston v. Rice and Cuniffe
  - Livingston v. Rogers
  - Livingston v. Simond
  - Livingston v. Van Cortlandt
  - Lloyd v. Sneathen
  - Lloyd and Lloyd v. Douglass
  - Lloyd and Lloyd v. Hewlet
  - Lloyd and Lloyd v. Williams
  - Lopez, Sarah, estate of
  - Low v. Graham
  - Lowrey v. Coen and Warner
  - Ludlow, Codwise, and Codwise v. Rhinelander and Ludlow, Codwise, and Codwise v. Constable and Constable
  - Ludlow v. Guernsey
  - Lundley v. Morris
  - Lyon v. Wells
  - Macaulay v. Ludlow
  - MacDavitt v. Barry and Barry
  - MacKintosh v. Willet
  - Marshall v. McMichael
  - Mason v. Griffiths
  - Maxwell v. Anthony, Christie, and Turell
  - Maxwell v. Franklin
  - Maxwell v. Swartwout and Griffin
  - McEvers v. Falkenham
  - McEwen v. Baker and Smith
  - McMinn v. Carpenter
  - Meeks v. Van Alstine
  - Miller v. LaMont
  - Miller v. Oudenaarde and Oudenaarde
  - Mitchell v. Woodward
  - Montarand v. L'Epine
  - Moore v. Hazen
  - Moore v. Manhattan Bank
  - Morrell v. Lawrence
  - Morris, Robert
  - Morris v. White
  - Morton v. Croghan
  - Morton v. White (Box 32, Reel 26-27)
  - Morton and Morton v. Seton
  - Mosby v. Mumford and Leeds
  - Moses and Co.
  - Mott and Carpenter v. Quimby See Container 27, Carpenter v. Mott
  - Mouchon v. Allard
  - Mount v. Bloomfield
  - Munn v. Riley and Wetmore
  - Murray v. Christie
  - Murray v. Nicoll
  - Murray v. Alsop and Pomeroy
  - Murray, Murray, and Sansom v. Arden
  - Murray, Murray and Sansom v. Schermerhorn
  - Murray, Murray and Sansom v. Trinas
  - Murray, Williams, and Griswold v. Fair American (brigantine)
  - Murray Sansom and Co.
  - Nathan v. Matlack
  - Neilson v. Berry and Mehelme
  - Neilson v. Blight
  - New York City v. Scott
  - Nichols case
  - Nicoll v. Anderson
  - Nicoll v. Woodhull and Hall
  - Nicoll and Thompson v. Columbian Insurance Co.
  - Nupiard v. Causaban
  - Oliver v. Hazen
  - Palmer, Benjamin, estate of
  - Parage v. Dale
  - Parker and Mann v. Parker and Parker
  - Peak v. Causaban
  - Pearsall v. Arnold
  - Pearsall v. Jarvis
  - Pell v. Cunningham and Cunningham
  - Pell v. Webbers
  - Pelton v. Ward
  - Pemberton v. Tier
  - Pendleton v. LeConte
  - People v. Croswell
  - People of the State of New York v. Byron
  - People of the State of New York v. Hoffman
  - People of the State of New York v. Leonard
  - Perry v. Price and Haywood
  - Person v. Campbell
  - Peters v. Gilbert
  - Pettit v. Causaban
  - Pettit v. Falkenham and Wilmerding
  - Pierson v. Morris
  - Quackenboss v. Ogilvie
  - Randall v. Hoffman and Van Allen
  - Ray v. Abeel, Lott, and Lutterloh
  - Remington v. Hunt
  - Renard v. Causaban
  - Reneau v. Causaban
  - Reqnaw v. Post
  - Rhodericks and Robinson v. Shivers and Rhodericks See Container 28, Fairchild v. Shivers
  - Ricketts v. Darley
  - Ricketts and Ricketts v. Livingston and Bancker
  - Rikeman, James
  - Rivington v. Dunlap
  - Robertson v. Cornack
  - Roff v. Moffit and Willet
  - Rogers and Rogers v. Cruger
  - Ross v. Rose and Rose v. Ross
  - Rourseem v. Causaban
  - Rowlett v. Stiles
  - Runion v. Bryant (Box 33, Reel 27-28)
  - Runion v. Smith and Smith
  - Rushmore v. Van Wyck
  - Russell v. Murphy
  - Rutgers v. Waddington
  - Saltus v. Hart and L'Epine
  - Sanches and Abrahams v. Ingraham
  - Sands v. Phelps and Edwards
  - Sands and Sands v. Thomas
  - Sansom v. Murray
  - Sarly v. Macauley and Macauley
  - Saunders v. Robins
  - Schenck v. Van Dorsten
  - Schuyler v. Ten Eyck
  - Schuyler v. Yates
  - Schuyler creditors v. Schuyler
  - Schuyler, Philip
  - Scott v. Campbell
  - Scribner v. Hickok
  - Seagrave and Constable v. Blair and Blair
  - Seaman v. Bedell, Poillon, and Bedell
  - Segara v. Montaudevert
  - Seguin v. Magnac and Magnac
  - Seton, Maitland, and Seton v. Low
  - Shannon v. Gamble
  - Shaw v. Stevenson
  - Shepherd v. Goadsby
  - Shoemaker v. McCormick
  - Sleight and Sleight v. Rhinelander
  - Smith v. Campbell
  - Smith v. Ferris
  - Smith v. Gerritsen
  - Smith v. Lazar
  - Smith v. Murray and Mumford
  - Smith v. Wickes
  - Smith and Smith v. Newberry and Jackson ex dem. Smith and Smith v. Newberry and Jackson ex dem. Smith and Smith v. Hoff
  - Smith, Richard
  - Smyth v. Atayataghronghts
  - Soderstrom, R.
  - Solomon v. Harris
  - Solomon v. Platt
  - Somarindike and Van Cortlandt v. Bogert
  - Somarindike and Van Cortlandt v. Smith
  - Springsteen v. Furman
  - Steinback v. Rhinelander
  - Steinmetz and Bell v. Curry
  - Steuben v. Casting
  - Stevens v. Mifflin
  - Stevenson v. Fraunces
  - Storey v. Cole
  - Stuyvesant v. Hebbard and Hebbard
  - Stuyvesant and Billings v. McKnight
  - Sullivan, Millan, and Williams v. Columbian Insurance Co.
  - Swartwout v. Cooper
  - Sweet v. Allen
  - Swift v. Reed
  - Taylor v. Nicoll (Box 34, Reel 28)
  - Terrason and Terrason v. Diligent (sloop)
  - Thompson v. Franks
  - Thompson v. Price and Haywood
  - Thompson v. Walton, Walton, and Walton
  - Thorne v. Heartt
  - Thurman v. Knox
  - Thurman, Thurman, and Roosevelt v. Frost
  - Tiebout v. Wardell and Co.
  - Titus and Titus v. Youngs and Youngs
  - Todd v. Falkenham and Wilmerding
  - Tompkins and Bingham v. Panton
  - Townsend, Joshua and Noah
  - Townsend (Mrs.)
  - Townsend v. Carman and Carman
  - Tredwell v. Gilbert
  - Tremain and Stout v. Foster and Carmer
  - Tucker v. Thompson
  - Turell v. Woodhull
  - Turner v. Young
  - Tyrrel v. Jones
  - Union Turnpike Corp. v. Jenkins
  - United States v. Barque Favorite
  - United States v. Constable
  - United States v. Duane
  - United States v. White, Shaw, and Titus
  - Van Cortlandt v. Jones
  - Van Cortlandt v. Judson
  - Van Cortlandt v. Olmstead
  - Van Cortlandt v. Belknap and Smith
  - Van DeWater v. Steward, Seely, and Doty
  - Van Hoesen v. Van Rensselaer
  - Van Horne v. Gale and Miller v. Gale
  - Van Ranst, Sears, and Kortright v. Crukshank and Crukshank
  - Van Rensselaer land patents
  - Van Zandt v. Brinckerhoff
  - Van Zandt v. Pearsall
  - Vaughan and Spooner v. Rhinelander
  - Verplanck v. Duncan
  - Voss and Graves v. United Insurance Co.
  - Waldron, Waldron, and Waldron v. Van Bremer and Van Bremer
  - Wardrop v. Macaulay
  - Waters v. Stewart
  - Watson v. Walton and Walton
  - Wawayanda v. Cheesecocks
  - Webb v. Nathan
  - Webro v. Causaban
  - Wilcox v. Phelps
  - Wilkes, Dickenson and Co. v. Langworthy
  - Wilkie v. Roosevelt
  - Willcock v. Ward, Ward, and Ward
  - Willetts v. Latoratt
  - Williams and Van Wyck v. DeHart
  - Willing and Willing v. Kortright
  - Wilson and Hirons v. Baldwin
  - Wilson and Hirons v. Van Allen
  - Wiltse v. Packwood
  - Woolsey v. Wardell
  - Wright v. Hewlett
  - Wright and Roe v. Wright
  - Yates assignee and Pollock v. Yates
  - Zabriskie v. Van Buskirk
  - Other legal papers (Box 35, Reel 28-29)
    - Affidavits, summons, and writs, 1775-1795
    - Agenda of cases
    - Agreements and arbitrations, 1784-1799
    - Financial papers of clients
      - Accounts, 1774-1800
      - Assignments, bonds, deeds, promissory notes, and releases, 1750-1800
    - Fragments
    - Legal receipts and acknowledgments, 1785-1804
    - Memoranda and lists of cases, 1782-1800
    - Miscellaneous documents re
      - Revolutionary War rents, 1778-1784
      - Land grants and patents, 1714-1786
      - Unidentified cases involving maritime insurance, admiralty jurisdiction, and charter ships, 1777-1801
    - Opinions by Hamilton
      - For Alexander Macomb respecting acts of British courts in districts comprising western posts
      - On bankruptcy law
      - On contract for carrying mail by stagecoaches
      - Regarding Jarvis-Greene deed, 20 Jan. 1797
    - Powers of attorney, 1783-1790
    - Statements of cases, opinions, and legal questions under consideration for litigation, 1781-1800
    - Unidentified briefs by Hamilton
    - Wills and legacies, 1732-1794
- Financial Papers, 1782-1804, n.d. (Box 36, Reel 29)
  Two volumes of account books and miscellaneous receipts and accounts.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Cash books, 1782-1804, (2 vols.) (Box 36, Reel 29)
  - Miscellany, 1784-1803, n.d.
- Family Papers, 1737-1903, n.d. (Box 37-38, Reel 29-31)
  Correspondence, financial papers, notes, and poetry.
  - 1737-1839, (15 folders) (Box 37, Reel 29-30)
  - 1840-1903, (5 folders) (Box 38, Reel 30-31)
  - Undated
    - Hamilton, Elizabeth
    - Hamilton, Rebecca McLane
    - Other family members
    - Miscellany
- Miscellany, 1711-1820, n.d. (Box 38-44, Reel 31-34)
  Certificates, clippings, essays, memoirs, military papers, notes on the collection, school exercises, reports, printed matter, and photocopies.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material.
  - Certificates (Box 38, Reel 30-31)
    - Hamilton, Alexander
    - Others
  - Clippings
  - Description of Kerelaw House, Stevenson, Scotland
  - Extracts from treaties with Spain relating to Louisiana and West Florida
  - Final report re settlement of accounts between the United States and individual states, 29 June 1793
  - Hamilton, Alexander
    - Estate
    - Last will and testament
    - School exercises
      - The Iliad of Homer, 1772-1773
      - Notes on Genesis and Revelations, 1773
  - Journal of trip to meet with Cayuga and other Indian tribes, 6-25 July 1795
  - King, Rufus
    - Essay on the position of the United States in reference to the French treaties, n.d.
    - Notes on Thomas Jefferson's letter of 15 Aug. 1785 to Charles Gravier Vergennes
  - Legislative acts, committee reports, and resolutions, 1762-1798, n.d.
  - L'Enfant, Pierre Charles, memorial presented to the Society of the Cincinnati, n.d.
  - Marriage agreement between Alexander Hamilton (grandfather) and Elizabeth Pollock (grandmother), with typescript and annotated copy, 15 June 1711
  - Memoirs relating to Hamilton
  - Memorials, petitions, and job applications, 1747-1793
  - Military papers (Box 39, Reel 31-32)
    - By period
      - American Revolution, 1775-1783
        - General file
        - New York Artillery Company pay book, includes notes by Hamilton on a variety of subjects, Aug. 1776-May 1777
      - Early national, 1787-1800
        - Appointments and promotions
        - Artillerists and engineers
        - Certificates and depositions
        - Court martial and imprisonment orders
        - General orders
        - Infantry regiments, (2 folders)
        - Manuals
          - Artillerists and engineers, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 40, Reel 32)
          - Cavalry, (2 folders)
    - Miscellany
    - Organizational plans and notes
    - Returns, miscellaneous and nonregimental
    - Rules and regulations
    - Supply contracts, orders, and price schedules
    - Tousard, Louis de
      - Memorandum re formation of a school of artillerists and engineers
      - "Report on the Fortifications of the Eastern Seaboard"
    - Uniforms
  - Miscellany
  - New York state (Box 41, Reel 32-33)
    - Schuyler, Philip, draft of law on harbor fortifications for New York, N.Y.
    - Legislative acts and committee reports
    - Harrison, Richard, notes on the debates in the ratifying convention, June-July 1788
  - Papers relating to New York state revenue, 1780-1782
  - Papers assembled in preparation of financial reports
  - Papers pertaining to United States relations with France
  - Papers relating to manufacturing
  - Papers relating to trade and commercial treaties between United States and Great Britain
  - Papers used in preparation of a report on the establishment of the mint
  - Poems
  - Randolph, Edmund, copy of resolutions submitted to the Constitutional Convention, 1787
  - Talleyrand-Périgord, Charles Maurice de
    - Essay on Fauchet's dispatch, with copy
    - Paper on public credit, with copy and translation
  - Transcripts of Hamilton's correspondence with Aaron Burr and an account of the duel by William P. Van Ness
  - Unidentified writings
  - United States appropriations and abstract of customs duty bonds for 1794, 1789-1798
  - United States Constitution, printed drafts with annotations by Hugh Williamson
  - Printed matter
    - Almanac, 1725
    - Bank of North America
    - Barton, William, "Remarks on the State of American Manufactures and Commerce," American Museum, June 1790
    - Extract from Proceedings of the New York State Society of the Cincinnati, 4 July-12 Aug. 1786
    - Jay, John
      - An Address to the People of the State of New York on the Subject of the Constitution
      - Report on Eastern Boundary Line
    - Paine, Thomas, Letter to the Late General George Washington When President of the United States (Box 42, Reel 33-34)
    - Statements of the Receipts and Expenditures of Public Monies During the Administration of the Finances by Robert Morris, 30 Aug. 1790
  - Notes on the Hamilton papers
    - Calendar of papers, 1749-1799, (3 folders)
    - Index to Hamilton manuscripts, vols. 31-37
    - Lists of papers in the former McLane-Hamilton series
    - Miscellany (Box 43, Reel 34)
    - Notes and card index to legal papers
    - Rough memoranda for an index, chiefly of papers not printed
  - Photocopies of letters to and from Hamilton, 1789-1820 (Box 44)
- 1998 Addition, 1780-1799 (Box 44)
  Letter from Nicholas Everton to Hamilton concerning legal matters and photocopy of page from a church register recording Hamilton's marriage to Elizabeth Schuyler.
  - First Reform Church, Albany, N.Y., photocopy of page from marriage register recording Hamilton's marriage to Elizabeth Schuyler, 1780 (Transferred from the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection) (Box 44)
  - Letter from Nicholas Everton to Hamilton re legal matters, 1799
- Oversize, 1775-1805, n.d. (Box OV 1-OV 3)
  Oversize material consisting of correspondence, reports, annotated drafts of the Constitution, writings, deeds, agreements, contracts, financial papers, certificates, lace samples, and printed matter filmed in their original location before removal to this series.
  Arranged according to the container from which the items were removed.
  - Oversize items consisting of correspondence, reports, annotated drafts of the Constitution, writings, deeds, agreements, contracts, financial papers, certificates, lace samples, and printed matter filmed in their original locations before removal to this series. (Box OV 1-OV 3)